

**Hemant Patkar** Scrum Certified Full Stack Developer



## **Basic Information**

Current Location: Mumbai Marital Status: Married

Date of Birth: 27<sup>th</sup> July 1987



## **Contact Me**

hemantpatkar.hsp@gmail.com **8082109966 / 7977070006** 

https://hemantpatkar.github.io



## **Professional Skills**

- Google Cloud / Azure Cloud
- Angular
- C#/.net Core / MVC / OOPS
- Okta SSO / OIDC •
- Microservices / WCF / Web API
- MS SQL / LINQ / Entity Framework
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Scrum Agile /Jira / Confluence
- CSS / Bootstrap 4



## **Certifications**

- Scrum Developer Certification
- **Azure Certification**
- **GNIIT Course from NIIT**

# **Domains Worked On**

- **E-Commerce**
- Warehousing
- **ERP**
- CRM
- **Human Resource Management**
- **Talent Management**



#### **Interests**

- Monsoon Trek
- **Playing Tabla**
- Watching Movie
- **Long Drives**
- **Listening Music**

## **Career Objective**



An MCA postgraduate having 10 years of experience in multiple domains. Seeking a position to utilize my abilities and skills in the Information Technology Industry that offers me professional growth and challenging work environment while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.



## **Project Experience**

[March 2021 - Till Now]

### Capgemini as Manager

- Total talent management app designed with microservices architecture in .net core and Angular, hosted on Google Cloud
- Designed worker process to sync data between App and SAP.
- Using Azure DEVOPS for task management and Pipelines for pushing the code.



### [Nov 2016 - March 2021]

#### **Ingram Micro as Lead Software Development Engineer**

- Implemented OKTA for login with OIDC implementation for ecommerce Enterprise SSO and mobile app.
- Microservice with ASP.net Core for Profile API with SAML used with Okta inline token to provide user information as a response to client application.
- Ecommerce Shopping Application with back office including SAP and Impulse Integration (MVC/Web API/WCF).
- Cisco Vendor Portal using MVC n-layer Architecture and APIs.
- Agile software development with Jira for all projects.



#### [Nov 2012 – Nov 2016]

#### Big Sun Technologies as Senior Software Developer

- Warehousing System with integrated Financials (C#.net and SQL).
- Online Support portal and Ticket system (C# ASP.net and SQL).
- ERP (Finance, Stock and Production) (Strong Oops Concept with
- Data migration for Upgrading old systems (MS SQL Server).
- Human Resource Management with mobile app integration (C# Asp.net with Web Services).



#### [Dec2011 – May2012]

#### Arête Technologies for MCA final year project

Shopping Cart for Net Spider India using ASP.net and MS SQL



#### **Education**

2012 Master of Computer Applications, Mumbai University 60.5% NCRD-Sterling Institute of Management Studies

**2009** BSC in Computer Science, Mumbai University 53.6%

## Strengths & Skills

- Strong verbal & communication skills. Strengths include team spirit, the ability to learn new concepts and quest for knowledge.
- Motivation and enthusiasm with single pointed focus and aptitude to learn are additional strengths. Methodical approach to work with perfection.
- Will to work in harmonizing the company's goals with personal growth and provide pleasant work environment.
- Self-confident and Trustworthy.